brisbanefestival.com.au 2019-04-02

# Privacy Policy

**1\. Our commitment to your privacy**

Major Brisbane Festivals Pty Ltd is the organiser of the Brisbane Festival.

This policy reflects our commitment to ensuring that our collection, holding, use and disclosure of information complies with the provisions of the Privacy Act 1988 ( **Act** ), in particular, the Australian Privacy Principles ( **APPs** ) set out in Schedule 1 of the Act.

You can download a copy of the Act at <https://www.legislation.gov.au/Details/C2017C00283>

**2.  Personal Information**

The Act provides that “personal information” means information or an opinion (including information or an opinion forming part of a database), whether true or not, and whether recorded in a material form or not, about an individual whose identity is apparent, or can reasonably be ascertained, from the information or opinion.

We take all reasonable steps to protect the personal information we hold from misuse, loss and unauthorized access, modification or disclosure.

**3\. Collection, use and disclosure of personal information**  
    ** **

**3.1 Information for customers**  
 **3.1.1 Collection of your personal information**

When you purchase your tickets to a Brisbane Festival event, in person, over the phone or online from third parties such as ticketing agencies (for example, Qtix) or our hired venues, they collect your personal information, including your:

  * Name;
  * Residential address;
  * Postal address;
  * Telephone numbers;
  * Email address;
  * Details of the performance you are buying tickets to;
  * Date of birth; and
  * Credit card details.

The terms of the third parties’ privacy policies apply to their collection, holding, use, and disclosure of your personal information. Those policies can usually be found on their websites.

Unless you tell them otherwise, the third parties will share your name, contact details and other personal information with us. Our privacy policy applies to our collection, use, and disclosure of your personal information, once it is disclosed to us by the third party.

Please note: Brisbane Festival is not given your credit card details by our ticketing agencies or our hired venues.

**3.1.2  Use of your personal information**

Our ticketing agencies and hired venues use your personal information in order to deliver your ticket, process your payment arrangements, contact you in the case of cancellation or major disruption of an event and replace lost tickets.

In general, the purposes for which we collect and use your personal information include:

  * Placing you on mailing lists either electronically or postal;
  * To inform you of activities, events and products that may be of interest to you, including festival news or upcoming events;
  * Submitting entries to events or competitions;
  * To assist with enquiries you may have about the festival;
  * To maintain our business records;
  * To seek donations or sponsorship;
  * To carry out transactions with you, such as to process payments and donations received by you; and
  * Any purpose that you would otherwise reasonably expect.

At any time, you may choose not to receive marketing material from us. On all of our direct marketing material, there is a notice providing you with the opportunity to “opt out” of receiving any further material.

If you no longer wish to receive marketing information from us, you can also contact our Privacy Officer (see section 6 below). Please allow 30 days for amendment of our records.

We also use your information, in anonymous form, for statistical purposes, to gain a better understanding of our audience.

**3.1.2 Disclosure of your personal information**

We may disclose your personal information to other organizations which provide us with marketing services, information technology services, or other services relating to our events.

We may also disclose your personal information if authorized or required to do so by law (for example, where we are required to disclose your personal information to a court in response to a subpoena).

We will not disclose your personal information for any other purpose without your consent.

**3.1.3 Your right to anonymity**

Where it is lawful and practicable to do so, you may undertake business with us without providing personal information. For example, you may purchase tickets to a Brisbane Festival event by cash payment, in person, over the counter, without providing personal information.

**3.2 Information for business associates**

**3.2.1 Collection of your personal information**

We may collect your personal information, including your:

  * Name;
  * Employer;
  * Work contact details including your email address; and
  * Personal contact details such as your phone number,

in person, over the telephone, by fax, or by email in order to undertake our daily artistic and administrative operations.

For example, we may have your contact details if you are our “point of contact” within an organization with which we do business.

**3.2.2 Use of your personal information**

We will only use your personal information for the business purpose for which it was collected.

**3.2.3 Disclosure of your personal information**

We will only disclose your personal information if necessary to achieve the business purpose for which it was collected.

**3.3 Information for job applicants (including volunteers)**

  * **Collection of your personal information**

If you are applying for a job with us, you may be required to provide us with certain personal information, including your:

  * Name;
  * Residential address;
  * Postal address;
  * Telephone numbers;
  * Email address;
  * Employment history; and
  * Educational background.

This information may be collected in your interactions with Brisbane Festival in person, over the telephone, by fax or email, as part of, or in relation to, your job application.

In considering your information, we may also collect information about you from the referees you nominate in your application.

**3.3.2 Use of your personal information**

We will only use your personal information for the purposes of considering your application and, if successful, your employment.

**3.3.3 Disclosure of personal information**

In considering your application, it may be necessary for us to disclose some of your personal information to third parties in order to verify the accuracy of that information.

We will disclose only such information as is necessary in the circumstances.

**3.4 Information for website users**

**3.4.1 Collection of your personal information**

Our website uses "cookies", which are pieces of data that are placed on your web browser containing details about your use of our website.

We use cookies to analyse user activity to improve the website. For example, to look at aggregate patterns like the average time users spend on different pages.

We may also use cookies to track your browsing habits on our website, and we may include that information in our systems alongside other personal information we may hold about you.

You can read more about how Google uses data sent from our website by visiting [How Google uses data when you use our partners' sites or apps](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/)

**3.1.2 Remarketing to website visitors**

We use remarketing services, such as Google AdWords Remarketing, to advertise Brisbane Festival online.

Remarketing services will display ads to you based on what parts of the Brisbane Festival website you have viewed by placing a cookie on your web browser.

Remarketing services allow us to tailor our marketing to better suit your needs and only display ads that are relevant to you.

If you do not wish to see ads from Brisbane Festival you can opt out in several ways:

  1. Opt out of Google’s use of cookies by visiting [Google’s Ads Settings](https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated).
  2. Opt out of a third-party vendor’s use of cookies by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/#!/).

**3.4.3 Third party sites**

Sometimes our website contains links to third party websites, for your convenience and information.

We are not responsible for the privacy practices of third party websites. We recommend that you review the privacy policies for each website you visit.

**3.5 information for Brisbane Festival social media followers**

Any information posted on Brisbane Festival’s social media pages including Facebook, Twitter and Instagram and/or communicated in chat areas becomes public information. While we strive to protect and respect your privacy, we cannot guarantee the security of any information you disclose via social media, a chat room or bulletin board.

We use aggregate information from our Facebook and Twitter accounts to better understand our audience, and answer your queries.

**4\. How we store and secure your personal information**

Your personal information may be stored in either hard copy or electronic format. 

Where we engage a third party service provider, we will make sure that appropriate data handling and security arrangements are in place. 

We are committed to keeping all personal information secure and have taken reasonable steps to prevent unauthorised access, modification or disclosure. We have implemented technology and security features to make our systems as secure as possible and to safeguard your personal information. 

We take reasonable steps to destroy or permanently de-identify any personal information after it can no longer be used.

**4.1 Sensitive information**

‘Sensitive information’ is a specific type of personal information, including information about your health, race, ethnic origin, political opinions, membership of political, professional or trade associations, religious or philosophical beliefs, sexual preferences and criminal history.

The APPs impose greater obligations on us regarding any collection, use or disclosure we make of your sensitive information. 

Usually, we do not collect sensitive information.  If for some reason we do need to collect your sensitive information, we will only collect it if:

(a)  you have expressly consented to us doing so;  
(b)  we are required to do so by law; or  
(c)  the collection is necessary to establish, exercise or defend a legal claim.

**5\. Access to personal information**

To obtain a copy of the personal information we hold about you, please contact our privacy officer (see section 6 below).

You will be required to complete and submit an access form.

You will also be required to provide proof of your identity. If you are applying by:

  * Post, email or fax – you must attach a certified copy of your identification to the access form;
  * In person – you must produce the relevant information to the privacy officer.

Documents that provide sufficient proof of your identity are:

  * Your current drivers license;
  * The identifying page of your current passport;
  * Your birth certificate; or
  * A statutory declaration by an individual who has known you for at least one year.

We will not charge you to access your personal information.

**6\. Correction of personal information**

We take all reasonable steps to ensure that the personal information we collect, use and disclose is accurate, complete and up-to-date.

However, the accuracy of that personal information depends to a large extent on the information you provide to us. To help ensure the accuracy of the personal information we hold about you, please inform the Privacy Officer (see section 6 below) if:

  * You become aware of any errors in the personal information we hold about you; or
  * There are any changes to your personal information, such as changes to your name, address or other contact details.

Please allow 30 days for amendment of our records.

**7\. Privacy Officer**

For further information about the personal information we hold about you, access to or correction of that information, or for any other privacy queries or complaints, please contact our privacy officer:

Telephone:  (07) 3833 5400  
Fax:  (07) 3833 5450  
Email:  brisbanefestival@brisbanefestival.com.au  
Address:  PO Box 384, Fortitude Valley, QLD 4006

We will do our best to resolve any complaint as quickly as possible, and in any event aim to respond to you within 30 days.  If you are not satisfied with our response to your complaint, you can refer the matter to the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner.

Online:  www.oaic.gov.au  
Mail:  GPO Box 5218, Sydney  NSW  2001  
Phone:  1300 363 992  
Fax:  02 9284 9666

**8\. Changes to this privacy policy**

We reserve the right to change this privacy policy at any time and to notify our customers, business associates and job applicants by posting an updated version of the policy on our website.
